Isaac M. Jordan – Software Engineer

London, United Kingdom IsaacJordan95@gmail.com

http://isaacjordan.me http://uk.linkedin.com/in/ijordan http://github.com/isaac-jordan

Summary

Professional software engineer with 5 years experience in small and large enterprise environments building innovative products aiming to be market leaders. Experienced in a variety of languages and technology stacks, mostly recently with Java/Kotlin, JavaScript, TypeScript, and AWS services (Lambda, SQS, DynamoDB, S3).

Work Experience

AWS (Amazon CodeGuru Profiler)

London, UK

Software Development Engineer II

Sep 2019 - Present

- Designed, implemented, and launched new user features in a new and ambiguous product area with a global team, such as simplified profiling visualisations, core onboarding workflow for new users, and new APIs to correlate data with other AWS services. Wrote the first public blog post.
- Took ownership over the console (front-end) infrastructure and codebase, ensuring a high quality bar was maintained as newer engineers took on front-end work and the service extended to 5 additional AWS regions. Personally improved page performance by 50% and reduced bundle size by 20%.
- Took on an informal engineering team lead role, mentoring other engineers through projects and regularly improving and simplifying development and operational processes. E.g. introduced Kanban and simpler prioritisation discussions, follow-the-sun on-call rotas, safer launch processes, weekly dashboard reviews, reusable infrastructure libraries (removing over 10k lines of code).

Amazon Edinburgh, UK

Software Development Engineer II

Sep 2018 - Sep 2019

- Integrated my team's video rendering API with a large Amazon Advertising product, involving global collaboration over several months. Utilised AWS Lambda/DynamoDB/S3 for a new micro-service mediator with automated alarming, along with new TypeScript/React components for the UI.
- Improved my team's development and release processes over time, e.g. introducing SonarQube for month-on-month code quality improvements, and new tools to track the team's operational load.

Amazon Edinburgh, UK

Software Development Engineer I

Sep 2017 - Sep 2018

- Launched a new programmatic video advertising program and increased ad performance by 10x in 6 months through rigorous experimentation, exceeding our team goal of \$500k sales.
- Other projects included improving customer privacy by scrubbing personally indentifiable information from logs within seconds, developing new front-end features to manage and discover internal video projects, and introducing new front-end test harnesses to cover previously untested code.

Amazon Edinburgh, UK

Software Development Engineer Intern

Jun 2016 - Aug 2017

- Created a patent-awarded prototype application to convert existing video content into personalisable videos in a fast (real-time) and automated fashion, using a Java/OpenCV pipeline.

TBR Global Chauffeuring

Glasgow, UK

Software Developer (Intern, followed by Part-Time)

Jun 2015 - May 2016

- Reduced data ingestion time by 95% for Emirates Airline jobs by preprocessing data using OpenAddressesUK and Google Maps APIs, saving hours of manual labour each week.

Chi Squared Innovations

Remote

Software Developer (Part-Time)

Sep 2014 - Jun 2015

Education

University of Glasgow

Glasgow, UK

BSc (Hons) in Computer Science (First Class)

2013 - 2017

- Received top-of-class prize in Year 3, and first prize at Glasgow University Hackathon 2015.